Cops or criminals. When you’re facing a loaded gun, what’s the difference?
The Departed is a drama, thriller, crime film directed by Martin Scorsese.
To take down South Boston's Irish Mafia, the police send in one of their own to
infiltrate the underworld, not realizing the syndicate has done likewise.
While an undercover cop curries favor with the mob kingpin, a
career criminal rises through the police ranks.
But both sides soon discover there's a mole among them.
Billy, played by Leonardo DiCaprio.
Colin, played by Matt Damon.
Costello, played by Jack Nicholson.
Dignam, played by Mark Wahlberg.
Queenan, played by Martin Sheen.
Mr. French, played by Ray Winstone.
The Departed is a 2006  crime thriller film directed by
Martin Scorsese and written by William Monahan.
It is both an English-language remake of the 2002 Hong Kong film Infernal Affairs and also loosely based on the real-life Boston Winter Hill Gang; the character Colin Sullivan is based on
the corrupt Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) agent John Connolly, while the character Frank Costello is based on Irish-American gangster and crime boss Whitey Bulger.
The film stars Leonardo DiCaprio, Matt Damon, Jack Nicholson, and Mark Wahlberg, with Martin Sheen, Ray
Winstone, Vera Farmiga, Alec Baldwin, Anthony Anderson and James Badge Dale in supporting roles.
The film takes place in Boston and the surrounding metro area,
primarily in the South Boston neighborhood.
Irish Mob boss Frank Costello (Nicholson) plants Colin Sullivan (Damon) as a spy within the Massachusetts State Police;
simultaneously, the police assign undercover state trooper Billy Costigan (DiCaprio) to infiltrate Costello's mob crew.
When both sides realize the situation, Sullivan and Costigan each attempt
to discover the other's identity before they are found out.
The Departed premiered at the Ziegfeld Theatre on September 26, 2006
and was released on October 6, 2006 by Warner Bros.
Pictures in the United States, with Media Asia
Distribution releasing in Hong Kong.
The film was a critical and commercial success, grossing $291.5 million on a budget of around $90 million and receiving acclaim
for its direction, performances (particularly of DiCaprio, Nicholson, and Wahlberg), screenplay, and editing.
It won several accolades, including four Oscars at the 79th Academy Awards: for Best Picture, Best Director for Scorsese (his only
personal Oscar win to date), Best Adapted Screenplay for Monahan, and Best Film Editing for editor Thelma Schoonmaker.
The film also received six nominations each at the 64th Golden Globe Awards (winning one) and the 60th
British Academy Film Awards, and two nominations at the 13th Screen Actors Guild Awards.
The film explores themes of police, undercover, boston,
massachusetts, gangster, irish-american.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.